

AKSHAYA NARAYANAN

Phone : (+49) 176 25874933

Email: akshaya.europe22@gmail.com

in LinkedIn : www.linkedin.com/in/akshaya-techy

Website : https://akshutechy.github.io/akshaya_pf/

• Schleusenweg 9, Münster 48147, Germany

Visa Type: BLUE CARD

National Series Availability: Immediate Joiner

ABOUT ME

•ISTQB Certified Tester with 6 years of experience in Manual and Automation Testing

•Exposure to Mobile and Web Automation

•Expert in Agile-Scrum and participating cross team activities, integrations and Sprint reviews

•Gained experience in five Web and two Mobile application projects

•Good understanding of Development stages SDLC, STLC and CI/CD

•Exposure to frontend and backend development in Python.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages Typescript, JavaScript, Python, HTML, CSS, Core Java, Gherkin, UNIX, Linux

Tools Selenium, Cypress, Playwright, WebdriverIO, Junit, Allure, Maven, Git, Jenkins,

JMeter, Cucumber, TestNG, Appium, Bitbucket, Eclipse, Postman,

VS Code, PHP storm, Bamboo, GitLab, GitHub Actions, Docker, XCode

Test Management Tools Jira, Kiwi tcms, TestRail, Xray

Databases MySql Server and MySql Workbench

SOFT SKILLS

Communication Skills and Analytical thinking, Prioritization and Time Management, Team/ Stakeholder management

CERTIFICATIONS

- ISTQB® Certified Tester Foundation Level
- Scrum Master

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software QA Engineer

Check24 Vergleichsportal GmbH, Münster, Germany [Mar 2024 - Present]

- Contributed to Android and iOS test cases in Mobile App automation using WebdriverIO Appium
- Contributed to Web automation using Playwright Typescript
- Involved in frame work development right from scratch and tried to achieve reduction in flaky tests.
- Coordinated with the Product manager to improve test cases
- Troubleshoot and run the tests in Bamboo pipeline.

QA Engineer

Crossbow Labs LLP, Bengaluru, India [Jul 2020 - Dec 2023]

- Design and develop automated testing using Cypress and WebDriverIO automation tool with JavaScript
- Verifying the REST API(JSON) using **Postman** which reduces manual efforts up to 70%
- · Communicating with off-shore clients in USA to troubleshoot issues while handling the Product and
- Suggested ideas to the Development team which contributed 10% procedure improvements
- Testing the response speed which should be within 3 seconds from server of the application (known as Performance) using **JMeter**
- Performed Functional, Browser compatibility, Database, Stress and Load Testing to ensure 100% quality

Test Engineer (Junior)

TeamLease Services Ltd, Chennai, India [Feb 2019 - Jun 2020]

- Performed end-to-end, Smoke, Sanity, Integration and Compatibility testing to ensure maximum quality and tracked defect in JIRA
- Coordinate with offshore team members and handled daily scrum calls with stakeholders.
- Enhanced the Product Quality with innovative ideas which increased 30% in betterment of process
- Involved in developing Automation test Scripts in **Selenium WebDriver** and **Cucumber** tool which reduced 80% of manual work and generate test reports using **TestNG** framework
- Maintained Automation codes with a basic understanding of Maven and Jenkins CI/CD pipeline

Freelance Testing Engineer (Contract Basis)

USA Based Clients, Remote [Nov 2018 - Jan 2019]

- · Assisted the User Acceptance Testing (UAT) team on issue clarification and resolution
- Drew the Flowchart of the entire website by analyzing various parameters since it was a requirement raised by the customer and prepared Test Scenarios and Cases to ensure 0% defect leakage
- Provided demonstration to Client Management Board members
- Defect Logging and tracking User stories in JIRA
- Participated and Managed Scrum meeting, Bug Scrub with Project Manager and other 10 Agile Scrum team members and provided regular feedback towards improvement of Quality

Tester Intern

QSpiders Testing Training Institute, Chennai, India [Jan 2018 - Oct 2018]

- Designed and documented traceability matrix (RTM)
- · Coordination and communication with the development team and track the issue till it is closed
- Prepared and executed Test methods focusing more on the crucial functionalities
- Carried out Cross Platform testing on different mobile applications including iOS & Android platform

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **Tamil** | **English**

Other language(s): German (A2 Level) | French (A1 Level)

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Post Graduate Diploma in Computer Applications

Annamalai University, Chennai, India [Jun 2019 - May 2020]

Executive Diploma in Marketing Management

Loyola Institute of Business Administration, Loyola College, Chennai, India [Aug 2015 - Jul 2016]

Bachelors In Mathematics

University of Madras, Chennai, India [Jun 2012 - Dec 2015]